Over this lecture, we had a brief introduction to testing in react apps and I did mention that you can
Bu derste, tepki uygulamalarnda test etmeye ksa bir giri yaptk ve daha
dive deeper, that there are whole courses or articles diving just into testing and I can only encourage
derinlere dallabileceinden bahsettim, tm kurslarn veya makalelerin testlere daldn ve sadece daha fazla bilgi edinmek istiyorsanz
you to dive deeper if you want to learn more about testing,
daha derinlere dalmanz neriyorum. test hakknda, bu
this is just a rough introduction.
sadece kaba bir giri.
One of the most important things when it comes to testing is the way you think about tests,
Test etmek sz konusu olduunda en nemli eylerden biri, testler
don't test unnecessary stuff because that unnecessary stuff often is the most difficult to test, if you're
hakknda dnme eklinizdir, gereksiz eyleri test etmeyin nk gereksiz eyler genellikle test edilmesi en zor olandr,
testing the whole workflow from I click a button to my state updates to then something changes in another
eer tm i akn test ediyorsanz bir dmeyi tklarm Benim durumum iin baka bir bileendeki
component,
deiiklikler deiiyor,
then you won't have fun simulating that. That will require a lot of difficult work and code where you
o zaman bunu simle etmekten zevk almayacaksnz. Bu, ok fazla zor i gerektirecek ve
need to mock the h to the p calls so that you don't actually reach out to the server during your tests
kodlar p arlarna ynlendirmeniz gerekecek, bylece testler srasnda sunucuya gerekten ulaamayacaksnz ve hepsi
and all of that isn't fun at all.
bu hi de elenceli deil.
And it's not only no fun, it's also redundant because we don't need to test if we can reach out to
Ve bu sadece elenmek deil, ayn zamanda gereksizdir, nk sunucuya ulaabileceimizi
the server,
test etmemize
we need to test does our reducer work correctly,
gerek yok, redktrmzn doru altn test etmemiz gerekiyor,
do we update our components correctly if the input changes,
eer girdiler deiiyorsa bileenlerimizi doru bir ekilde gncelliyoruz,
maybe we want to test do we find a correct prop if we click a certain button.
belki biz Belirli bir dmeyi tklarsak, doru bir pervane bulmay denemek isteriz.
All these things can be easily tested in isolated unit tests
Btn bunlar, izole nite testlerinde kolayca test edilebilir ve
and this really is the way to think about it
bu, onu dnmenin ve
and the way I encourage you to practice.
pratik yapmanz tevik etmenin yolu.